Finding Aid for John Harvey Kellogg Papers, 1832-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Lectures, Speeches, and Related Materials
  - January-February 1904, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Home Health Culture February 25, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Obesity February 29, 1904 (Box 4)
  - February-March 1904 Lectures to Medics on Gynecology (17 pts.), .PDF and .ZIP files
    - ETC February 29, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Pelvic Inflammation March 1, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Pelvic Inflammation March 2, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Pelvic Inflammation (Chronic) March 3, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Hemorrhoids March 4, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Uterine Lacerations March 9, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Uterine Cancers March 10, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Uterine Fibroids March 11, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Laparotomy March 14, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Hysterectomy March 15, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Retroversions[?] March 16, 1904 (Box 4)
    - The Abdominal Walls March 17, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Abdominal Muscles March 18, 1904 (Box 4)
  - April-September 1904, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Lecture to Senior Medical Students on topic of pneumonia, April, 4 1904, April 5, 1904 (2 pts.) (Box 4)
    - Lecture to Senior Medical Students on topic of physiologic medicine April 6, 1904 (Box 4)
    - The New Dietary May 5, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Sanitarium Methods June 30, 1904 (Box 4)
    - How Not to Mind the Weather September 15, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Lecture on topics of varicose veins, appendicitis, and eczema September 22, 1904 (Box 4)
  - November-December 1904, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - How We Cultivate Disease November 3, 1904 (Box 4)
    - The Treatment of So-called Incurable Disorders By the Physiologic Method November 10, 1904 (Box 4)
    - The Training of Chronic Invalids December 1, 1904 (Box 4)
    - Gymnastics December 29, 1904 (Box 4)
  - January 1905 Lecture on Dietetics (5 pts.), .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 4)
  - January-March 1905, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Municipal Health or How to Make Battle Creek the Healthiest City in All the World January 31, 1905 (Box 4)
    - How the House Gets Afire and How to Put it Out February 9, 1905 (Box 4)
    - How Sick People Get Well March 30, 1905 (Box 4)
  - April-July 1905, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - How Can A Sick Man Get Well? April 20, 1905 (Box 4)
    - How Can A Sick Man Get Well Quick? May 11, 1905 (Box 4)
    - How Does the Sick Man Get Well? May 25, 1905 (Box 4)
    - The Heart May 29, 1905 (Box 4)
    - How to Make Battle Creek the Healthiest City in All the World (stereopticon lecture) June 27, 1905 (Box 4)
    - How Christians Should Eat July 27, 1905 (Box 4)
  - October-December 1905, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Untitled October 19, 1905 (Box 4)
    - The Cold Air Cure October 23, 1905 (Box 4)
    - Dedication Exercises of the Philadelphia Sanitarium October 31, 1905 (Box 4)
    - The Sure Way to Health November 9, 1905 (Box 4)
    - Graduating Exercises November 15, 1905 (Box 4)
    - The Way Out November 16, 1905 (Box 4)
    - Mexico December 14, 1905 (Box 4)
    - Talk to employees about ownership of the Sanitarium, its denominational basis, etc. December 28, 1905 (Box 4)
  - January-February 1906, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture January 15, 1906 (Box 4)
    - The Liver January 18, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Blood Pressure January 18, 1906, January 18, 1906 (2 pts.) (Box 4)
    - Blood Pressure in Internal Disorders February 1, 1906 (Box 4)
    - The Natural Diet of Man February 8, 1906 (Box 4)
  - April-June 1906, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture April 2, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Graduating Exercises April 24, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Question Box Lecture May 7, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Hygienic Lessons from the Earthquake May 14, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Question Box Lecture May 28, 1906 (Box 4)
    - The American Cradle May 31, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Question Box Lecture June 11, 1906 (Box 4)
    - How Does a Sick Man Get Well? June 14, 1906 (Box 4)
  - July-September 1906, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture July 2, 1906 (Box 4)
    - The Old Way and the New July 5, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Talk to Women July 31, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Untitled talk regarding Sabbath Observance August 2, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Old and New Ideas about Disease August 2, 1906 (Box 4)
    - How Incurable Are Cured? August 9, 1906 (Box 4)
    - What is the Natural Principle of Healing? September 19, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Untitled talk on missions given by Dr. C. C. Creegan September 19, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Chinese Dress and Customs (talk given by Mrs. Frank A. Keller) September 20, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Life--What Is It? September 22, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Course in Physiologic Therapeutics September 25, 1906 (Box 4)
  - October 1906 Talks to Junior Medical Students (6 pts.), .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 4)
  - October-December 1906, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Course in Physiologic Therapeutics October 2, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Hydrotherapy October 8, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Question Box Lecture October 18, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Question Box Lecture November 8, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Summary of Address of welcome to Chautauqua Managers November 14, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Question Box Lecture November 22, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Question Box Lecture November 26, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Dr. Kellogg's First Word (re Sanitarium and Sanitarium tax suit) December 1906 (Box 4)
    - Question Box Lecture December 17, 1906 (Box 4)
    - Atwater Calorimeter (Given by Francis G. Benedict) December 31, 1906 (Box 4)
  - January-August 1907, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Essentials of Health January 22, 1907 (Box 4)
    - Vital Coefficients January 24, 1907, January 31, 1907 (2 pts.) (Box 4)
    - Colon Disease: Its Etiology, Pathology, Diagnosis and Treatment (article taken from Modern Medicine), June 1907 (Box 4)
    - The Anti-Toxic Diet July 18, 1907 (Box 4)
    - Health Perils in the United States (lecture given by Kellogg and Prof. Irving Fisher) July 29, 1907 (Box 4)
    - The Sanitarium System August 8, 1907 (Box 4)
  - October 1907, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Outdoor Life October 10, 1907 (Box 4)
    - How to Live Well One Hundred Years October 17, 1907 (Box 4)
    - Untitled talk by Kellogg and Dr. Wm. G. Anderson (Box 4)
    - University of Michigan Alumni Banquet talk October 24, 1907 (Box 4)
    - The Scientific Basis of Vegetarianism October 29, 1907 (Box 4)
    - Oatmeal October 31, 1907 (Box 4)
  - November-December 1907, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Remarks at National Purity Conference Banquet November 5, 1907 (Box 4)
    - Vital Resistance November 14, 1907 (Box 4)
    - The Cold Air Cure December 19, 1907 (Box 4)
  - February-July 1908, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Measuring a Man February 6, 1908 (Box 5)
    - The Efficient Life March 12, 1908 (Box 5)
    - How the Body Defends Against Disease March 26, 1908 (Box 5)
    - The Blood; How It Defends the Body in Health and Disease April 9, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Ancient Medical Notions and Modern Medical Science April 16, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Conversational Club Banquet April 22, 1908 (Box 5)
    - The Blood--Pressure April 30, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Untitled talk by Karl Mann and Kellogg June 25, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture June 29, 1908 (Box 5)
    - The Evils of Conventional Dress July 7, 1908 (Box 5)
  - August-September 1908, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture August 17, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture and The Simple Life August 27, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture August 31, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Helpers Meeting September 2, 1908 (Box 5)
    - How to Live the Simple Life September 3, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture September 24, 1908 (Box 5)
  - October-November 1908, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The International Congress on Tuberculosis October 8, 1908 (Box 5)
    - How the Body Defends Itself Against Disease October 15, 1908 (Box 5)
    - High Life November 12, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Untitled lecture given by Horace Fletcher November 16, 1908 (Box 5)
    - Constipation December 3, 1908 (Box 5)
  - January-May 1909, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Sleep January 28, 1909 (Box 5)
    - How the Body Heals Itself April 8, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Divine Healing April 10, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Rational Methods April 22, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture April 26, 1909 (Box 5)
    - How the Body Heals Itself May 13, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Stomach, Liver and other Viscera May 20, 1909 (Box 5)
    - The Blood-Pressure May 27, 1909 (Box 5)
  - June-July 1909, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Blood-Pressure June 3, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Coefficients June 17, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Evils of Civilization June 24, 1909 (Box 5)
    - The Blood July 8, 1909, July 15, 1909 (2 pts.) (Box 5)
    - Manual Swedish Movements July 22, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Sugar July 29, 1909 (Box 5)
  - August-December 1909, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Magical Curative Power of Water August 5, 1909 (Box 5)
    - The Liver August 19, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Vital Economics (given by Dr. Horace Fletcher) September 2, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Digestion September 5, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Talk to Domestic Science Class September 21, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Physical Education October 7, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Pellagra Tuberculosis October 28, 1909 (Box 5)
    - Friendly Germs December 9, 1909 (Box 5)
  - 1910-1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Index to Question Box Lectures for 1910, 1911 (Box 5)
  - January 1910, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture January 3, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The Beginnings of Hydrotherapy January 6, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture January 10, 1910 (Box 5)
  - April-June 1910, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Porto Rico [Puerto Rico] April 4, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Why Flesh Eating is Wrong April 14, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture May 2, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The Battle Creek Sanitarium Method May 5, 1910 (Box 5)
    - How to Live Sanitariumwise May 12, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The Possibilities of Preventative Medicine June 1, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture June 6, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture June 9, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture June 16, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Health and Efficiency Rally June 20, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Talk at Banquet of Christian Endeavor Convention June 30, 1910 (Box 5)
  - July-September 1910, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Is the Human Race Degenerating? July 21, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture July 25, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The Battle Creek Sanitarium System August 4, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Digestion August 11, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Stereopticon Lecture August 25, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Health Hints from Europe (by S. S. McClure) and Battle Creek Sanitarium Principles (by J. H. Kellogg) August 29, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The New Hygiene September 1, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture September 12, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture September 26, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Our Devoted Friend, the Liver September 29, 1910 (Box 5)
  - October-December 1910, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - How to Keep on Good Terms with Your Liver October 6, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture October 24, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The New Hygiene October 27, 1910, November 3, 1910 (2 pts.) (Box 5)
    - The Physiological Necessity of Hard Work November 10, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The Conventional Beefsteak November 17, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture November 21, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture November 29, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture December 1, 1910 (Box 5)
    - Some Features of New Hygiene December 8, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The Battle Creek Idea December 15, 1910 (Box 5)
    - The Liver December 29, 1910 (Box 5)
  - January 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Clinical Dietetics, Lecture I January 16, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Clinical Dietetics January 17, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Clinical Dietetics January 19, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Food January 19, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Reception to Drs. Morse and Eggleston January 23, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 21 January 23, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Race Degeneracy January 26, 1911 (Box 5)
  - February 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - What Shall I Do to be Saved? February 2, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture February 6, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 22 February 9, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 23 February 15, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Why Eat Flesh? February 16, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Are We Too Much Civilized? February 23, 1911 (Box 5)
  - March 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - What Disease is Doing For Us March 2, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Tendencies Toward Race Degeneracy (Box 5)
    - The Antitoxic Diet March 9, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Experience of A. W. Grabe; Question Box Lecture March 13, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Untitled lecture on race degeneracy and muscles March 16, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Talk to Y.M.C.A. Convention March 19, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 25 March 20, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 26 March 27, 1911 (Box 5)
  - April-May 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Some New Ideas About Digestion April 13, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Race Degeneracy April 16, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 28 May 15, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Some Features of Race Degeneracy May 18, 1911 (Box 5)
    - The Miracle of Healing May 20, 1911 (Box 5)
    - How to Live Long and Well May 25, 1911 (Box 5)
  - June 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Beginning of the Battle Creek Idea June 1, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 29 June 8, 1911 (Box 5)
    - The Non-Flesh vs. the Flesh Diet; The Evils of Tobacco Using June 15, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Art of Wholesome Living June 29, 1911 (Box 5)
  - July 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture 31 July 3, 1911 (Box 5)
    - The Stomach July 13, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 34 July 24, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Race Deterioration July 27, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 35 July 31, 1911 (Box 5)
  - August 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Liver August 3, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Food August 10, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 37 August 17, 1911 (Box 5)
    - The Living Temple or the Miracle of Life August 26, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 39 August 28, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Where are we going? August 31, 1911 (Box 5)
  - September 1911, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture 40 September 4, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Tendencies Toward Race Degeneracy (reprint from New York Medical Journal), September 9, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 41 September 11, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Question Box Lecture 42 September 18, 1911 (Box 5)
    - Untitled talk on food September 21, 1911 (Box 5)
  - January 1912, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Talk to Patients January 20, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture January 22, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture 43 January 29, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Monthly Meeting of the Health and Efficiency League of America January 30, 1912 (Box 6)
  - February 1912, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture 44 February 5, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture 45 February 19, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Symposium of the Battle Creek Idea February 20, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Women's Dress February 22, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Question Box and Stereopticon Lecture February 29, 1912 (Box 6)
  - March 1912, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture 48 March 4, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Tobacco March 7, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 18, 1912 (2 copies) (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 25, 1925 (Box 6)
  - April 1912, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture 50 April 8, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Digestion April 11, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Talk to the Patients April 18, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Stereopticon Lecture April 25, 1912 (Box 6)
  - May-June 1912, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Our Natural Diet May 9, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Christian Science and Divine Healing June 1, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Graduating Exercises of the Battle Creek Sanitarium School of Health and Home Economics June 12, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture June 17, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Twenty-Seventh Annual Commencement exercises June 18, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture June 24, 1912 (Box 6)
  - July-December 1912, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Bacteriotherapy July 18, 1912 (Box 6)
    - Yogurt Ferments in the Treatment of Intestinal Disorders in Infants July 27, 1912 (Box 6)
    - The Simple Life in Practice August 15, 1912 (Box 6)
    - The New Human Race October 3, 1912 (2 pts.) (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture December 2, 1912 (fragment) (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture December 9, 1912 (Box 6)
  - February-Mar 1913, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture February 24, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Digestion March 3, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 3, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 10, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Dietetics for Nurses: Feeding in Fevers March 11, 1913, March 13, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Radium March 13, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 17, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Feeding in Fevers, No. 3 March 17, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 27, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 31, 1913 (Box 6)
  - April 1913, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture April 7, 1913 (Box 6)
    - The Measuring of a Man April 10, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture April 14, 1913 (Box 6)
    - The Stomach April 17, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture April 21, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Untitled Stereopticon lecture on Russia and digestion April 24, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture April 28, 1913 (Box 6)
  - May 1913, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Muscles May 1, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture May 5, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Foods May 8, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture May 12, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture May 19, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Meat Germs May 22, 1913 (Box 6)
  - July-December 1913, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Human Health as a Natural Asset July 31, 1913 (lecture given by Irving Fisher), July 31, 1913 (Box 6)
    - First Annual Reunion of Sanitarium Patients August 12, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Relation of Public Health Work to Race Degeneracy September 10, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture September 15, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture October 13, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture November 3, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture December 2, 1913 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture December 15, 1913 (Box 6)
  - January-February 1914, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture: Diabetes January 26, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture February 2, 1914 (Box 6)
    - The Stomach February 5, 1914 (Box 6)
  - April 1914, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture April 6, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture April 16, 1914 (Box 6)
    - The Great White Plague April 20, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture April 23, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture April 27, 1914 (Box 6)
    - The Stomach and Stomach Surgery April 30, 1914 (Box 6)
  - May 1914, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture May 4, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture May 14, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture May 21, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture May 25, 1914 (Box 6)
  - June 1914, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture June 1, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Untitled stereopticon lecture June 4, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture June 11, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture June 14, 1914 (Box 6)
    - How the Body Combats Germs June 18, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture June 25, 1914 (Box 6)
  - July 1914, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - The Home Sanitarium July 6, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture July 9, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture July 15, 1914 (Box 6)
    - The Colon July 16, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture July 20, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Race Betterment July 23, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture July 27, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture July 30, 1914 (Box 6)
  - August-December 1914, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Commencement, Normal Sch. of Physical Education August 19, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Poison Habits--Tobacco August 27, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Address of Welcome to the Members of the American Electro-Therapeutic Association September 15, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Why Laughing Is An Aid to Digestion October 12, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture October 12, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Health Training October 15, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture October 22, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture December 28, 1914 (Box 6)
  - January-September 1915, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture January 18, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture January 25, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 29, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture (portions) May 24, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture September 20, 1915 (Box 6)
  - October-December 1915, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Welfare Rally at Sanitarium Gymnasium October 7, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture November 1, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture November 15, 1915 (Box 6)
    - The Disinfecting Power of Food November 18, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture December 13, 1915 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture December 27, 1915 (2 copies) (Box 6)
  - January-March 1916, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Divine Healing January 29, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Stereopticon Lecture February 3, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Stereopticon Lecture February 24, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 6, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 13, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture March 30, 1916 (Box 6)
  - April-June 1916, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture April 27, 1916 (Box 6)
    - How the Body Fights Disease May 4, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Stereopticon Lecture May 25, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Baccalaureate Sermon to the Nurses Graduating Class given by Bishop W. S. Lewis June 3, 1916 (Box 6)
  - July-November 1916, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture July 24, 1916 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture August 22, 1916 (Box 6)
    - The Case Against Sugar November 9, 1916 (Box 6)
  - March-April 1917, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture March 26, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture April 9, 1917 (Box 6)
    - How to Live One Hundred Years April 12, 1917 (Box 6)
    - The Waste of Food April 19, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture April 30, 1917 (Box 6)
  - May-July 1917, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture May 7, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Raising the Blockade May 10, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture May 14, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture May 28, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture June 14, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Germs July 12, 1917 (Box 6)
  - November-December 1917 undated 1917, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Question Box Lecture November 12, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture November 26, 1917 (Box 6)
    - Question Box Lecture December 17, 1917 (Box 6)
    - The Virtues and Dangers of Milk as a Food undated 1917 (Box 6)
  - 1918-1922, .PDF and .ZIP files (Box 7)
    - Technic of Operation for Repair of the Ileocaecal Value January 1918 (Box 7)
    - The Battle Creek Idea at the Sanitarium Parlor July 29, 1918 (Box 7)
    - Talk to the Faculty at Dr. Kellogg's residence November 12, 1919 (Box 7)
    - Nuts needed as Supplementary Foods October 8, 1920 (Box 7)
    - Battle Creek Ideals, Mar 12 1921 (Box 7)
    - Practical Eugenics May 20, 1921 (2 copies) (Box 7)
    - Untitled greeting on occasion of open of Battle Creek Sanitarium Clinic November 1, 1921 (Box 7)
    - Taking One's Inventory December 26, 1921 (Box 7)
    - The Battle Creek Sanitarium is Always Progressing December 1922 (Box 7)
  - 1923-1926, .PDF and .ZIP files
    - Diet in Relation to the Teeth January 1923 (Box 7)
    - Clean Certified vs. Denatured Pasteurized Milk June 1923 (Box 7)
    - The Pecan: A Meat-Bearing Tree June 12, 1923 (Box 7)
    - Untitled address October 10, 1923 (Box 7)
    - Untitled address December 14, 1923 (Box 7)
    - A New Method of Studying Posture and Development March 25, 1924 (Box 7)
    - What Makes the Tired Business Man Tired? June 28, 1924 (Box 7)
    - Untitled address given before the Six O'clock Club of Lansing March 20, 1924 (Box 7)